Welche Kontakte hatten Sie vor dem 7. Oktober zu Menschen aus Gaza?
Many people here had a good relationship
with people from Gaza.
People don’t know this, but
life is stronger than everything.
And we are very close.
This is like half a mile,
the distance is about half a mile,
and my husband
used to be the manager of two dairy farms here.
Today he's only the manager of one,
but his dairy farms were all...
he's a very good professional in what he does,
so many merchants from Gaza used to have
working relationships with him and
because they came to buy things,
and sell things,
and with many of them,
friendships developed.
I had Gazans at my wedding here, at the kibbutz.
I had Gazans at my dinner table.
More than once.
And when I studied
Middle Eastern studies in Tel Aviv University,
and I wanted to research about the
economic policy of Hamas
I interviewed merchants from Gaza in my living room.
So yes,
we had a very close relationship with them.
Up until October 7.